Kevin Mbui Software Developer

<u>kevinmushan@gmail.com</u> • +(254) 791-560-183 github.com/kevinmbuicode/ • linkedin.com/in/kevinmbui/ • mushan.tech

Summary Statement

I'm a Frontend Software developer with 2+ years of experience. I have increased code delivery speed by 7%, enhanced site speed by 11%, and boosted site relevance with SEO by 15% in 6 months while regularly training novices. I am seeking to leverage proven leadership and expertise to become the next senior software engineer.

Work Experience

Frontend Software Developer, Hybrid Marketing Group

Hybrid Marketing Group, Nairobi, KE

May 2020 – June 2022

- I formed and guided a team on various tasks, including Design, Development and Marketing.
- I oversaw the redesign of a website, added heatmaps and boosted SEO leading to 38% sales increase.
- I developed, reviewed, and delivered websites with 100% on-time record and according to service level objectives.
- I integrated various payments methods such as Stripe and PayPal.

Property Manager, John's Apartments

John's Apartments, Nairobi, KE

July 2020 – Present

- I collect and manage rent, solve internal conflicts, identify areas affecting the tenants and solving any found issues.
- I Initiate projects that upgrade the apartments, and maintaining the apartments.
- I establish trust and understanding in everybody for a comfortable home environment for everyone.
- I seek feedback from tenants about how new implementations may or have affected them.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Agriculture

Moi University, Kitale, KE

September 2018 – December 2021

• Relevant Coursework: Leadership & Communication.

Technical Skills

Expert (★★★★★): HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Git version control, Architectural Patterns.

Advanced (★★★★★): IBM Cloud, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), ES6.

Familiar (★★★☆☆): Node.js, OpenShift, Docker, Kubernetes, MongoDB, Redux Toolkit.

Soft Skills

- Communication, Empathy/Emotional Intelligence, Patience, Negotiation
- Problem-solving/Critical Thinking, Time Management
- Teamwork/Collaboration, Adaptability, Self-motivated, Leadership, Creative Thinking, Ability to Accept Feedback

Certifications

- Full Stack Cloud Developer (Coursera/IBM), January 2022
- Cloud Application Development Foundations (Coursera/IBM), January 2022

Honors & Awards

Full Stack Cloud Development Capstone Project (Coursera), January 2022

Projects (Business & Technical)

Full Stack Cloud Development Capstone Project

A web app to access a central database for all dealerships in USA, conditionally allow only logged in users to leave reviews, any user to view sorted reviews by state and branch. Use IBM NLU to determine the sentiment of the review, containerize and deploy to Kubernetes.

- Technology used: Django, Kubernetes, IBM cloud, Html, CSS, IBM Cloudant.
- Link: https://github.com/kevinmbuicode/Cloud App Development Capstone

Modern Ecommerce with Stripe Checkout

A beautiful modern ecommerce website. Integrated with Stripe payments. Accomplished using routes, API calls, and a great User Interface (UI), and User Experience (UX).

- Technology used: React, Stripe, Sanity.io.
- Link: http://www.mushan.tech/

Cryptocurrency Watch

A web app to list the top 100 currencies in the market. The goal was to create awareness of cryptocurrencies and show case the top winners and losers of the day easily. And a chart to show the trend of a selected coin in the past 24 hours, 30 days, 3 months and 1 year.

- Technology used: React, Material UI, Chart.js, Vercel.
- Link: http://www.mushan.tech/

Volunteer Work

Assist fellows fix bugs.

Courses

- IBM Full Stack Cloud Developer, (Coursera)
- The Odin Project